Profile

Data-driven strategist with experience in interface analysis with a foundation in education and customer support. I bring value to my organization by identifying data discrepancies, working cross-team to diagnose issues, communicate to stakeholders, and follow through to resolution. I lead with a human-centered and empathetic approach. My experience and background have given me an ear for listening and a knack for understanding complex concepts, facilitating processes, and innovating to improve workflow.

Professional Experience

Systems Analyst

Navigating Cancer

Feb. 2016 – present

- Improved data quality by managing errors found in interface engines for all channels and outbound documents
- Resolved application issues by utilizing SQL to investigate and analyze data
- Proactively identified and resolved clinic interface and data flow issues
- Streamlined Jira workflow by using JQL to compile weekly and monthly reports
- Prevented any data gaps by monitoring DataDog alerts and dashboards related clinic connectivity
- Implemented and owned the feature Appointment Reminder Service for clinics customers
- Owned ceremonies to support Kanban project management
- Utilized interface engines to investigate clinical, billing, demographic and appointment data issues
- Meticulously dealt with strict privacy procedures and sensitive data related to confidential patient medical information
- Delivered training and onboarding of new members of the analyst and support team
- Created and maintained reports in SalesForce to improve visibility into bug trends and patterns
- Revitalized documentation in Confluence and Google Drive to improve application knowledge
- Owned escalation and priority process of active Jira board

Equipment Appraiser

Industrial Appraisals

Nov. 2009 – Feb. 2016

- Collected, organized and managed large amounts of data about property such as industrial machinery and equipment in diverse industries, including food packing and construction.
- Led business development and market expansion by coordinating design of website, defining keywords for SEO.
- Increased functionality of report filing process by developing and implementing new techniques using Microsoft Office.
- Designed a new process using Excel which expedited on-site appraisal work, increased capacity to meet goals and improved work efficiency.

Elementary and Substitute Teacher

Bellevue and Everett School Districts

Sept. 2008 – June 2012

- Administered, evaluated, and recorded assignments for students across multiple grade levels.
- Quickly implemented lesson plans for a variety of subject and grades in high-energy, fast-paced environments. Managed, assessed and met the needs of different types of learners.
- Facilitated learning in English, math, science and other subjects.
- Met goals independently and in sync with team of teachers while communicating effectively with community of families and staff.

Programming Skills

Languages: SQL , JavaScript, HTML, Ruby

Applications: SalesForce, Jira, Mirth, DataDog, Confluence, Jive, Github, Tableau,

SendGrid, Zoom, Slack/MatterMost, Snowflake

Education

University of Washington Full Stack Web Development

2022-2023

- HTML & CSS
- JavaScript
- Node.js
- React

City University of Seattle Master's Degree in Teaching

2006-2007

- 3.75 GPA Studied Multiple Intelligences, Cognitive Development
- Full time elementary school teacher as well as substitute all other grades, subjects
- High school football coach

Pacific Lutheran University Bachelor's Degree

1999-2004

- B.A. in Art and Minor in Communications, studied Computer Science courses in HTML
- Lettered 4 years on football team
- Volunteered at local middle and elementary schools

Programming Courses

Treehouse: HTML, CSS

DataCamp: SQLUdemy: SQL, Ruby